Antonio Vásquez Briones

+56992935020 - advasquezbr@gmail.com

Las Condes -Santiago - Chile

Professional Profile

Automation Engineer with +3 years of experience working in education, development and field service in Control Systems, Industrial Electronics, Networks, and Microcontrollers. Primarily focused on development and integration of new technologies. Excellent interpersonal and communication abilities, and possess a wide range of technical and programming skills. Enjoys being a part of a team, as well as managing, motivating and training others, and thrives in challenging working environments.

Education

- Universidad del Bío-Bío, Concepción Chile.
 Automation Engineer, 2014 -Bachelor of Science Degree in Engineering 2013 (Ingeniería Civil en Automatización)
- Liceo Industrial Metodista, Coronel Chile.
 Electronics Technician, 2007.

Professional Experience

04-2018 to date

Synopsys Chile Ltda. Vitacura, Santiago

- Research and Development Engineer II, Product Validation Team.
- Working mainly on application and development of automated benchmark test for several company software products oriented to Integrated Circuits developments for worldwide presence clients. (micro-processors, smartphones, artificial intelligence industry, etc.)
- Advanced linux scripting and grid computers usage on a daily basis.

03-2015 to 03-2018

Universidad Tecnológica de Chile INACAP Concepción-Talcahuano (*Technological University of Chile*)

- Full-time Academic of the Electrical, Electronics and Automation department, teaches mainly Control Systems, PLC's, Microcontrollers and Industrial Networks classes. Teaches and trains adult and youth.
- SENCE Corporate Training Programs like Industrial Instruments and PLC.
- Design and Implementation of Domotic Technologies at facilities.

07-2013 to 03-2015

Liceo Industrial Metodista, Coronel

- Full-Time teacher for High-School Electronics Technicians, works with teenagers at social risk.
- Lead Teacher of the Robotics Group. First Prize at Inacap Robotics Challenge 2014.

07-2011 to 07-2012

Industrial Instruments Field Technician

• Commissioning and troubleshooting at several power plants in BíoBío Region, Chile. Serves as English translator for companies from various locations around the world.

03-2009 to 12-2012

Universidad del Bío-Bío, Campus Concepción.

Teaching Assistant at Calculus, Motion Control and Systems courses.

Additional Skills

C/C++, Object Oriented Programming, Java, Processing, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Python, Linux Scripting, Assembly, Siemens Step 7, ABB IRC5 Robot System.